The war's not over until the last man comes home.
Missing in Action is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Joseph Zito.
American servicemen are still being held captive in Vietnam and it's up to one man to bring them home in
this blistering, fast-paced action/adventure starring martial arts superstar Chuck Norris.
Following a daring escape from a Vietnamese POW camp, Special Forces Colonel James
Braddock (Norris) is on a mission to locate and save remaining MIAs.
Col. James Braddock, played by Chuck Norris.
Tuck, played by M. Emmet Walsh.
Sen. Porter, played by David Tress.
Ann, played by Lenore Kasdorf.
Gen. Trau, played by James Hong.
Jacques, played by Pierrino Mascarino.
Missing in Action is a 1984 American action film directed
by Joseph Zito and starring Chuck Norris.
It is set in the context of the Vietnam War POW/MIA issue.
Colonel Braddock, who escaped a Vietnamese prisoner of war camp ten years earlier, returns to
Vietnam to find American soldiers listed as missing in action during the Vietnam War.
The film was followed by a prequel, Missing in Action 2: The Beginning (1985), and a sequel, Braddock:
Missing in Action III (1988), it is the first installment in the Missing in Action film series.
The first two Missing in Action installments had been filmed back-to-back with the intent to have the
first film involve the POW years of Braddock (as directed by Lance Hool) be the first film.
However, it was determined that the commercial prospects were stronger
with the film directed by Zito involving the POW rescue.
As such, Hool's film was turned into Missing in Action 2 and labeled as a
prequel that detailed events before those in Missing in Action.
It is the first of a series of films themed around the Vietnam War POW/MIA issue that were produced by Menahem Golan and Yoram
Globus and released under their Cannon Films banner, with whom Norris would have a long professional relationship.
Norris later dedicated these films to his younger brother Wieland.
Wieland, a private in the 101st Airborne Division, had been killed in June 1970
in Vietnam while on patrol in the defense of Firebase Ripcord.
The film, however, was criticized heavily as being a preemptive cash-in on the Rambo franchise, with both the
first and second Missing in Action films being released just months before the second Rambo film.
Despite the overwhelmingly negative reception from critics, the film was a
commercial success and has become one of Chuck Norris's most popular films.
It was also Chuck Norris's first film with The Cannon Group.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietnam
veteran, martial arts, vietnam, patriotism.
The tone is emotional and intense.